fivestaralliance.com 2019-06-19

# Privacy Policy | Five Star Alliance

Last Updated 10/31/2018

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices you should first contact Five Star Alliance's privacy policy administrator, by phone at +1 (703) 836-0692.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

### Overview

Five Star Alliance takes your privacy very seriously, and we appreciate the fact that by using our service you are placing a great deal of trust in us. Our service has been built from the ground up with your privacy foremost in mind. We know that privacy is an important issue for our clients, and it is thus an important issue for us. We make it our highest priority to secure and protect the confidentiality of the personally identifiable information that you provide to us.

This policy clearly explains the type of personally identifiable information we gather when you use the Five Star Alliance service found on our web site: [www.fivestaralliance.com](http://www.fivestaralliance.com/). This privacy policy describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. This policy also outlines the steps we have taken to safeguard the data we collect, and it explains the control we provide to you over the data we collect.

### Information we collect

The only personally identifiable information we collect is information that you voluntarily provide to us. This includes your email address and optional demographic information (such as zip code, gender and year of birth), collected when you sign up for our newsletter, and the information you provide to us when you book a hotel reservation. Booking information, required by hotels, includes name, address, contact information, and the credit card details used to hold a reservation.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputers, and enforce our agreements. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use or delete your information to provide you services [contact us here](https://www.fivestaralliance.com/luxury-hotel-experts/contact-us). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

### How we use the information we collect

We use your information only for the explicit purposes for which you provide it. When you sign up for our newsletter, we use your email address for the purpose of delivering the specified newsletter to you. You will only receive the requested number of emails. We do not share your email address or your optional demographic data with any other party, unless you explicitly allow us to do so. We consider an explicit agreement to be a clear "opt-in" choice-a choice that requires you to take an action. We do not consider a box checked by default to be an explicit agreement.

When you book a hotel reservation with us, we deliver your information directly to the relevant hotel, and not to any other party. We store a copy of your booking information on our computers so that you can retrieve that information when you return to our site. However, for security purposes, we do not store your entire credit card number on our servers. Instead, we only store the last four digits of the number.

When you use our "Email a Friend" feature, we use the names and email addresses provided by you for the sole purpose of sending an email from you to the recipient. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. We do not store any names or email addresses collected for this site feature.

### Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial/bankruptcy proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety of the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

If Five Star Alliance is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information.

### How we protect your information

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

The security of your personally identifiable information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as your credit card number) on our reservation form, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

Five Star Alliance uses the leading security technology available, including SSL, to protect and secure your information. We are certified by the industry-leading TRUSTe and use the security services of [Norton Secured Powered by DigiCert](https://trustsealinfo.websecurity.norton.com/splash?form_file=fdf/splash.fdf&dn=www.fivestaralliance.com&lang=en). DigiCert, Inc., with the acquisition of Symantec Website Security, is the leading global provider of digital certificates. To learn more about SSL, and for more information on our security certification, [please click here](https://trustsealinfo.websecurity.norton.com/splash?form_file=fdf/splash.fdf&dn=www.fivestaralliance.com&lang=en) or on the Norton Secured logo.

### Tracking Technologies

We, Five Star Alliance, and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

We use cookies to store the information you provide when you search for hotels (which might include location, activities, and/or dates) so that you don't have to re-enter that same information for new searches. We also use it to improve our service by helping us gauge our effectiveness in helping you find and book the ideal luxury hotel. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at feedback (at) fivestaralliance.com.

We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use Flash cookies or HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

### Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. If you are outside of the EU, our partner may use technologies such as cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [CLICKING HERE](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) and [HERE](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served all advertising. You will still continue to receive generic ads.

### How we share information

We do not share your profile with other third parties, other than the instances detailed in the following two paragraphs.

The information you provide to us when you book a travel reservation is delivered directly to the relevant travel supplier, and is not shared with any other party. This information includes what you've provided us when making your reservation, including your name, address, contact information, and credit card details.

The information you provide when you sign up for our newsletter, including email address and optional demographic information (such as zip code, gender, phone number), is not shared with other parties unless you explicitly allow us to do so. All explicit agreements will be "opt-in", rather than "opt-out". This means that by default we will not share your information, unless you take an action that allows us to do so.

We may provide your personally identifiable information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personally identifiable information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

### Updating your information

We strive to give you full control over the information you provide to us. To unsubscribe from our newsletter and all promotional communications, we provide clear instructions on our web site (via the newsletter link found on every page). You may also unsubscribe via the link at the bottom of all emails delivered to you, or you may unsubscribe by sending us by email.

Due to the nature of the travel industry's inventory systems, including the Global Distribution System (GDS), it is not currently feasible to automatically update the details of a reservation over our web site. Thus, should you need to make an update to your booking information, we ask that you contact us. We will be happy to assist you. You may reach us by phone at +1 (703) 836-0692, and links to our contact information, are provided on every page of our site.

### Links to 3rd Party Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Five Star Alliance. If you submit personally identifiable information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

### Social Media Widgets

Our web site may include social media features such as the "share this button" or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Changes to this policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the changes taking effect.

In addition, as our business changes, we may buy or sell various assets. In the event all or a portion of the assets owned or controlled by Five Star Alliance, or any subsidiary or affiliated entity, are sold, assigned, transferred or acquired by another company, the information from and about our sites' users may be among the transferred assets.

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Five Star Alliance  
1050 Connecticut Avenue NW #65462  
Washington, DC 20036 USA  
+1 (703) 836-0692  
<https://www.fivestaralliance.com/>

**See also:**

Five Star Alliance Terms

How Five Star Alliance Protects and Respects Your Data
